- [Adam] Hello, my name is Adam Wilbert,
and I'd like to welcome you
to Learning Relational Databases.
In this course, I'm going
to give you an overview
of the planning steps that
you should move through
before you start development
in order to ensure
that your system works as expected.
I'll start with an
overview of what exactly
a relational database is and
how its structure differs
from the spreadsheets
that you might be used to working with.
And I'll outline some of
the hidden difficulties
that can arise if the
structure of your data
isn't fully considered
before development begins.
Then we'll discover the
database development lifecycle
and use it as a guide for
moving through the process
of thinking about our
specific data storage needs.
Finally, we'll talk about all of the rules
that we've identified
about how the database
needs to function and
start translating them
into the components that will make up
the actual relational database.
And along the way, we'll
discuss design considerations
that'll make the database
easier to construct
and easier to maintain.
So I'd like to thank you for joining me
in learning relational databases.
Now let's get started.